Register of the Eric Cyril Bellquist Papers, 1928-1979
Hoover Institution Archives
- SUBJECT FILE, 1928-1979
  - Germany
    - Cables and dispatches (Folder 7)
    - Concentration camps (Folder 8)
    - German Library of Information - Facts in Review
      - 1939-1940 (Folder 9)
      - 1940 (Folder 10)
      - 1941 (Folder 11)
    - Hitler Youth. Translation of The Nazi Primer - Official Handbook for Schooling the Hitler Youth (Folder 12)
    - Media (Folder 13)
    - Notes (Folder 14)
    - Politics and government
      - General (Folder 15)
      - Office of the United States High Commissioner for Germany
        - General (Box 42, Folder 1)
        - Education (Folder 2-5)
        - Memoranda (Folder 6)
        - Reports (Folder 7)
        - Reports (Box 43, Folder 1)
      - Printed matter
        - General (Folder 2-4)
        - Government (Folder 5)
        - Government (Box 44, Folder 1)
  - Greenland (Folder 2)
  - Hoover, Herbert (Folder 3)
  - India (Folder 4)
  - Institute of Inter-American Affairs (Folder 5)
  - Institute of International Education (Folder 6)
  - International Information Administration (Folder 7-8)
  - Italy
    - General (Folder 9)
    - Italian Library of Information (Folder 10-11)
    - Italian Library of Information (Box 45, Folder 1-4)
  - Japan (Folder 5)
  - League for Supreme Court Independence (Folder 6)
  - League of Nations
    - Printed matter (Folder 7-8)
    - Printed matter (Box 46, Folder 1-2)
    - Reports (Folder 3-5)
  - Lithuania (Folder 6)
  - Malta and Yalta Conferences of 1945 (Folder 7)
  - Malta and Yalta Conferences of 1945 (Box 47, Folder 1)
  - Middle East (Folder 2)
  - Military governments (Folder 3)
  - National Defense Executive Reserve (Folder 4)
  - National Republic (Folder 5)
  - Netherlands (Folder 6)
  - North Atlantic Treaty Organization (Folder 7)
  - Norway
    - General (Folder 8)
    - Articles (Folder 9)
    - Norwegian Information Service
      - Norway Digest
        - 1946-1947 (Folder 10)
        - 1947 (Folder 11)
        - 1948 (Box 48, Folder 1)
      - Nyatt fra Norge, 1946-1953 (Folder 2)
    - Notes (Folder 3)
    - Politics and government (Folder 4-5)
    - Ukens nyatt fra Norge
      - 1942 (Folder 6-7)
      - 1942-1943 (Folder 8)
      - 1943 (Folder 9)
      - 1944 (Box 49, Folder 1)
      - 1945 (Folder 2)
  - People's Lobby (Folder 3)
  - Poland (Folder 4)
  - Princeton Listening Center (Folder 5)
  - Propaganda
    - General (Folder 6)
    - Articles (Folder 7)
    - Bibliography (Folder 8)
    - Bibliography (Box 50, Folder 1)
    - Propaganda Analysis (Folder 2-3)
    - Reports (Folder 4-5)
    - Reports (Box 51, Folder 1)
  - Psychological warfare (Folder 2)
  - Public opinion
    - General (Folder 3)
    - Articles (Folder 4)
    - National Opinion Research Center (Folder 5)
    - Notes (Folder 6)
    - Printed matter (Folder 7)
    - World Association for Public Opinion Research (Folder 8)
  - Rome Conference, 1959 (Folder 9)
  - Scandinavia
    - General (Folder 10)
    - Articles (Folder 11)
    - Education (Folder 12)
    - Notes (Folder 13)
    - Printed matter (Folder 14)
    - Speeches and statements (Folder 15)
  - Spain (Folder 16)
  - Sweden
    - General (Box 52, Folder 1-2)
    - Articles (Folder 3)
    - Cables and dispatches (Folder 4)
    - Embassy (Folder 5)
    - Media (Folder 6)
    - Memoranda (Folder 7)
    - Notes (Folder 8)
    - Politics and government (Folder 9-11)
    - Politics and government (Box 53, Folder 1-2)
    - Printed matter (Folder 3-6)
    - Speeches and statements
      - General (Folder 7)
      - Government officials (Folder 8)
    - Swedish Information Service
      - General (Folder 9)
      - Current Sweden
        - Environment Planning and Conservation (Box 54, Folder 1)
        - Human Environment (Folder 2)
        - Social Change (Folder 3)
        - View Point
          - 1971-1974 (Folder 4)
          - 1975-1977 (Folder 5)
        - Working Life (Folder 6)
    - Swedish Institute (Folder 7)
    - Tyskland Gar (Folder 8)
  - Thailand
    - General (Folder 9)
    - Press Summaries
      - 1954 (Folder 10)
      - 1955 (Box 55, Folder 1-2)
    - Propaganda
      - Fliers (Folder 3)
      - Pamphlets. Includes translations (Folder 4-6)
    - United States Information Service (Folder 7)
  - Tom Mooney Molder's Defense Committee (Folder 8)
  - Turkey (Folder 9)
  - Unitarian Service Committee (Folder 10)
  - United Nations
    - General (Folder 11)
    - American Association for the United Nations (Folder 12)
    - Conference on Freedom of Information, 1948
      - General (Box 56, Folder 1)
      - Press releases (Folder 2)
    - Memoranda (Folder 3)
    - Printed matter (Folder 4-7)
    - Proposals and resolutions (Folder 8-9)
    - Reports (Box 57, Folder 1-2)
  - United States
    - General (Folder 3-4)
    - Articles (Folder 5-6)
    - Education (Folder 7)
    - Elections
      - General. Includes Democratic Party only (Box 58, Folder 1)
      - 1962. California primary (Folder 2)
      - 1964
        - Democratic National Committee (Folder 3-4)
        - Democratic Party (Folder 5)
    - Foreign policy (Folder 6)
    - Labor and labor unions (Folder 7)
    - Labor Party (Folder 8)
    - League of Women Voters of the United States (Folder 9)
    - Media
      - General (Folder 10-11)
      - General (Box 59, Folder 1)
      - Federal Communications Commission (Folder 2)
    - Memoranda (Folder 3)
    - Newsletters (Folder 4)
    - Notes (Folder 5)
    - Operation Alert (Folder 6)
    - Politics and government (Folder 7-8)
    - Printed matter
      - General (Folder 9-10)
      - General (Box 60, Folder 1-6)
      - General (Box 61, Folder 1)
      - Defender, The (Folder 2)
      - Government (Folder 3)
    - Reports (Folder 4-7)
    - Republican Party (Box 62, Folder 1)
    - Speeches and statements
      - General (Folder 2)
      - Government officials (Folder 3)
    - Supreme Court (Folder 4)
  - United States Advisory Commission on Information (Folder 5-6)
  - United States Department of the Army (Folder 7)
  - United States Department of War (Folder 8)
  - United States Information Agency (USIA)
    - General (Folder 9)
    - Memoranda (Box 63, Folder 1)
    - Press releases (Folder 2)
    - Printed matter (Folder 3-4)
    - Reports (Folder 5)
  - United States Office of Strategic Services (Folder 6)
  - University of California at Berkeley
    - General (Folder 7)
    - Academic Senate (Folder 8)
    - Department of Political Science (Folder 9)
    - Notes (Folder 10)
    - Office of the Dean of Students (Folder 11)
    - Office of the Chancellor (Box 64, Folder 1)
    - Printed matter. Primarily includes ephemeral material relating to student unrest, strikes, and anti-Vietnam protests during the 1960's (Folder 2-6)
    - Printed matter (Box 65, Folder 1-6)
    - Printed matter (Box 66, Folder 1-4)
    - U.C. Regents (Folder 5)
  - Vietnam (Folder 6)
  - War Crimes (Folder 7)
  - Workers' Defense League (Folder 8)
- OVERSIZE MATERIAL, 1944-1945
  - Organizational charts from the Office of War Information, two scrapbooks and one hand drawn political cartoon (Box 67)
- INDEX CARD FILES, n.d.
  - Bibliographic card file (Box 68-69)
- PHONOTAPES
  - "America's Leading Lady" sound recording undatedPart 1: (1) Fru Ulla Alm-Lindström; (2) Secretary Arne Björnberg. Part 2: (1) Professor Eric C. Bellquist; (2) Birgitia Valberg; (3) Fröken Kerstin Hesselgren, Mrs. Eleanor Roosevelt. (2 reels) Use copy reference number: 81092_a_0007829 (Tape-cabinet Tape cabinet)
- PHONORECORDS
  - Sound recording of Marian Anderson singing "Ack Varm LLand Du Skona," Radiotjanst, Office of War Information 1945 January 2, 2 discs, with one a copy of the other; Use copy reference number: 81092_a_0002841 (Record-cabinet Record cabinet)
  - Voice of America 1970 July-December
- MOVING PICTURE
  - "The Living Stream," 16mm film, 1951 January 23 and February 10 (Film-shelf Film shelf)
- PHOTOGRAPHS, 248 prints, 16 postcards / 9 envelopes (Photo-file Photograph file)
  - 129 prints depicting West German Bundestag members visiting the United States, 1950 (Folder A)
  - 9 prints and 16 postcards, 1949 (Folder B)
    Includes 1 print of Elmer Davis, 1 print of Sumner Wells, 1 print of Polish farmers, and 1 print of the United States Information Service organizational chart.
  - 7 prints depicting a campaign promotion in California (Folder C)
  - 51 prints depicting Sweden, 1926-1948 (Folder D)
    Includes 9 prints of the 1948 elections, 10 prints of King Gustavus V, 9 prints of the Swedish Parliament, 9 prints of the Swedish Military, and 3 prints of political cartoons.
  - 8 prints depicting Norway (Folder E)
    Includes 1 print of King Haakon VII, and 1 print of President Carl Hambro of the Norwegian Parliament.
  - 17 prints depicting Denmark, 1920-1940 (Folder F)
    Includes 4 prints of the Danish Parliament, 3 prints of elections, 3 prints of the Danish Military, 2 prints of Foreign Minister Peter Munch, 2 prints of Prime Minister Theodore Stauning, 1 print of Nazi leader Fritz Clausen, and 1 print of commanding Officer General von Kaupisch.
  - 7 prints depicting Finland, 1930-1940 (Folder G)
    Includes 2 prints of Field Marshall Karl Mannerheim, 1 print of President Lauri Relander, 1 print of President Risto Ryti, 1 print of Foreign Minister Erkko, and 1 print of the Finnish Parliament.
  - 2 prints depicting the League of Nations, 1930 (Folder H)
  - 6 prints (Folder mI)
    Includes 2 prints of the League of Nations, 1 print of President Lauri Relander, 1 print of the Norwegian Parliament, and 1 print of Danish government officials.